[{"Question":"Which of the following is NOT a public sector insurance company?","option 1":"United India Insurance Company Limited","option 2":"The New India Assurance Company Limited","option 3":"SBI Life Insurance","option 4":"General Insurance Corporation of India","answer":"SBI Life Insurance"},{"Question":"As per the recommendations of the National Statistical Commission, the Base Year of the GDP Series in India was revised from 2004-05 to ______ with effect from January 2015.","option 1":"2011-12","option 2":"Â 2013-14","option 3":"2005-06","option 4":"Â 2009-10","answer":"2011-12"},{"Question":"To which of the following sectors of the economy do Basel III norms belong?","option 1":"\"Banking \"","option 2":"Capital market","option 3":"Automobile","option 4":"Aviation","answer":"\"Banking \""},{"Question":" Which Indian finance minister was Indiaâ€™s delegate to the World Monetary Conference at Bretton Woods in 1944?","option 1":"Â KC Neogy","option 2":"CD Deshmukh","option 3":"John Mathai","option 4":" RK Shanmukham Chetty","answer":" RK Shanmukham Chetty"},{"Question":"The Reserve Bank of India introduced a comprehensive regulatory framework for NBFC-MFI on __________.","option 1":"10-Dec-15","option 2":"02-Dec-11","option 3":"8-Dec-2013â€¯","option 4":"05-Dec-12","answer":"02-Dec-11"},{"Question":"The ______ was nationalised in the year 1949.","option 1":"Union Bank of India","option 2":"Â Reserve Bank of India","option 3":"Imperial Bank of India","option 4":"Central Bank of India","answer":"Â Reserve Bank of India"},{"Question":"Who is known as the father of Blue Revolution in India?","option 1":"Verghese Kurien","option 2":"Sam Pitroda","option 3":"Hiralal Chaudhuri","option 4":"M.S. Swaminathan","answer":"Hiralal Chaudhuri"},{"Question":"Labour Intensive Technique would get chosen in aâ€“","option 1":"Labour Surplus Economy","option 2":"Capital Surplus Economy","option 3":"Developed Economy","option 4":"Developing Economy","answer":"Labour Surplus Economy"},{"Question":"The Surplus earned by a factor other thus land in the short period is referred as â€“","option 1":"Economic Rent","option 2":" Net Rent","option 3":" Quasi-Rent","option 4":"Super-Normal Rent","answer":" Quasi-Rent"},{"Question":"The Relationship between rate of interest and consumption level was firstly estimated byâ€“","option 1":"Amartya Sen","option 2":"Milton Freedman","option 3":" Irwing Fischer","option 4":"James Duezan Berry","answer":"Milton Freedman"},{"Question":"Due to worldwide great depression, â€˜New Dealâ€™ was declared by?","option 1":" Abhraham Lincon","option 2":"Benzamin Frankllin","option 3":"J.F. Kennedy","option 4":" Roozwelt","answer":" Roozwelt"},{"Question":"Rent is a cost paid forâ€“","option 1":"Land","option 2":"Restaurant","option 3":" Building","option 4":"Factory","answer":"Land"},{"Question":"The Production of a commodity mostly through the natural process is an activity ofâ€“","option 1":"Primary Sector","option 2":"Secondary Sector","option 3":"Tertiary Sector","option 4":"Technology Sector","answer":"Primary Sector"},{"Question":"The Social Accounting system in India is classified intoâ€“","option 1":" Assets, Liabilities and Debt Position","option 2":"Public sector, Private Sector and Joint Sector","option 3":" Income, Product and Expenditure","option 4":"Enterprise, Households and Government","answer":" Income, Product and Expenditure"},{"Question":"_______________ is the value of dismantle material of the built-up property after useful period.","option 1":"Scrap Value\t","option 2":"Salvage Value","option 3":"Market Value","option 4":"Book Value","answer":"Scrap Value"},{"Question":"_______________ is the estimated resale value of an asset at the end of its useful life.","option 1":"Scrap Value\t","option 2":"Salvage Value","option 3":"Market Value\t","option 4":"Book Value","answer":"Salvage Value"},{"Question":"Fund containing money set aside or saved to pay off a debt or bond is called-","option 1":"Sinking Fund","option 2":"Mutual Fund","option 3":"Saving Fund","option 4":"None of the above","answer":"Sinking Fund"},{"Question":"The Gradual Loss in the Value of Property due to its use, wear and Tear, Obsolescence is called-","option 1":"Appreciation\t","option 2":"Depreciation ","option 3":"Net Worth\t","option 4":"Total Loss","answer":"Depreciation "},{"Question":"A voluntary arrangement between two or more parties that is enforceable by law as a binding legal agreement is known as __________","option 1":"Job","option 2":"Loan","option 3":"Contract","option 4":"Mutual fund","answer":"Contract"},{"Question":"A tender is advertised in ______ ","option 1":"newspapers","option 2":"business environment","option 3":"domestic markets","option 4":"sellers","answer":"newspapers"}]
